Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Does it smell good?
Lady Cao.
Peace to Your Highness.
Please rise, Cao.
You seem to be in good spirits.
Wenyi whines every day until I bring her out to play.
This mischievous little goblin gives me a headache.
Even if they wished for it,
others couldn't have such a headache.
Can I hold you for a second?
Aiya, princess Wenyi, aiya.
Behave yourself with Concubine Sourire.
Greet Concubine Sourire.
Concubine Sourire.
No worries. It's sweet when
a child isn't shy with strangers.
Give me a kiss.
And this side.
Here, be careful not to crease Your Highness's dress.
I have something to tell Your Highness.
It's so beautiful outside in spring.
I was just going to take a stroll
in the Garden of Dawning Spring.
Please excuse me.
I bid Your Highness goodbye.
Cao.
You have something to tell me ?
Having regained her status,
Consort Fleur summoned me to
the Palace of Earthly Honor yesterday.
There is nothing wrong with that.
You have always been close with her.
Now that her title has been restored,
you should congratulate her.
Certainly.
Congratulatory gifts have already been sent.
However, Consort Fleur asked about
Your Highness's activities over the
period of her confinement.
An intelligent woman such as yourself
can surely respond to her questions with propriety.
Whatever you say
depends on your plans for the future, Lady Cao.
What plans would I have?
I am just following Your Highnees's lead.
Still, Consort Fleur was your old master.
Although she was unkind to you and the princess at times,
she aided in promoting your status after all.
Her rank and family background
are far superior to my own.
It's only natural if you plan to be close to her.
Your Highness need not speak in riddles.
Dull-witted as I am, I do know that
Consort Fleur's regained favor and status
will pass like the blooming of an orchid cactus.
She's an arrow approaching the end of its flight.
I want a peaceful life for Wenyi and myself,
so I won't be taking any risks.
Cao, you have a perceptive mind and a keen intellect
to which few people can compare.
In fact, I do not wish that
you drift apart from Consort Fleur.
Since I have entrusted the princess
and myself to Your Highness,
I will follow only Your Highness's orders.
Why would I lean towards her?
I understand Your Highness's request.
And I will not disappoint Your Highness.
Cao, you understand when to advance and when to withdraw.
I have nothing to worry about.
Since Consort Fleur has inquired about me,
I will use her same methods against her.
What are her thoughts about her reinstatement?
She's been reveling in the feeling of it
but is also afraid of losing favor again.
With her previous fall from favor,
and having heard about what happened to
Consort Astuce and Noble Lady Fuca,
she is quite wary of Your Highness.
She's seen me as her arch-enemy for all this time.
Of course, I view her the same way.
Your Highness will certainly have ways to deal with her.
I will do what little I can.
There is one more thing, however.
Your Highness and I have no vital interests in common.
To be vulgar, it's an alliance based on short term interests.
When our interests no longer align,
we may go our separate ways.
Given my humble status, I understand that
I can never contend with Your Highness.
Therefore,
I am afraid I may not be of much help to Your Highness.
Cao, you are refreshingly candid.
Your concern is the same as my own.
As of yet, I still do not have any children.
Princess Wenyi is as fair as jade and snow.
I would like her to become my
honorary daughter after we succeed
so we can be each other's support.
What do you think, Cao?
If that were to happen, then we all would be at ease.
Your Highness's prospects are boundless.
It would be Wenyi's blessing
to receive Your Highness's care.
Cao, your hairpin looks familiar.
I saw it in His Majesty's treasury once.
It must have been granted to you by His Majesty.
Indeed, but it was just a small gift.
Cao, you have really beautiful hands.
Your nails look delicate
with just some jasmine oil on them.
But if you painted them with winter jasmine petals,
this unique touch would surely please His Majesty.
I thank Your Highness for the advice.
Dr. Wen, you are leaving in such a rush today.
You did not even have any tea.
My Lady, please don't trouble yourself to walk me out.
Concubine Sourire's herbs are still on the stove.
I am worried that if the servants lose track of time,
the herbs will lose their effect.
Is Concubine Sourire ill?
No,
they are preparing the Immortal Jade Maiden Powder
for Her Highness's complexion.
Those young servants are heavy handed
so I have to watch over it myself.
I thought it was something urgent.
His Majesty is very fond of Concubine Sourire right now.
Given His Majesty's grace, she doesn't need such luxurious face powder.
Concubine Sourire is at the height of her favor.
Her doorstep must be weathered from all the visitors.
I have to keep my distance, even as her sister.
But sir, you are bustling around to
"sew an extra flower onto her beautiful brocade."
My Lady, what makes you say that?
I've been in a foul mood lately.
Please pardon my offense.
But I know my words are to no avail.
No one remembers the extra flower sewed on a brocade,
but charcoal sent on a snowy day touches one's heart deeply.
Dr. Wen, I believe you understand this well.
Preparing medicinal herbs is my duty.
And that's why I also devote myself to your
herb supplies and routine pulse-taking.
I don't mind "adding a flower to the brocade."
But I sincerely hope,
whether it is you or Concubine Sourire,
that there will never be "a snowy day"
when my skills must be "your charcoal."
Dr. Wen, I hope that you will see
Sourire and me as equals
and care for us equally well.
My Lady, I will attend to the good health
of you and Concubine Sourire.
Nothing other than this is on my mind.
Lunar, walk Dr. Wen out.
Yes, My Lady.
Take care, Dr. Wen.
My Lady ...
Meizhuang, why are you standing outside in the cold?
You should be careful not to get a cold.
What brings Your Highness to my humble residence today?
Don't you need to spend time with His Majesty
to seek favor for Consort Fleur?
Please don't be angry.
That's why I come here today.
Please allow me to explain.
I'm tired. I want to rest.
And I need to visit Her Majesty after that.
Please leave.
I know you are angry with me,
but at least allow me a chance to speak.
Have you lost faith in the years
we spent together as sisters?
Come in.
Why is there no one about in your palace?
Where are the servants? Why aren't they with you?
The Household Department
is distributing summer clothing today.
I sent the servants there to collect it.
It's nothing like your opulent palace
with crowds rushing forward to serve it.
The head of the Household Department, Mr. Jiang
even personally delivers the clothes for your servants.
I know
that you don't care about His Majesty's favor.
Did you say that
because of Consort Fleur's reinstatement?
All right, then tell me
was it you who suggested to
His Majesty to reinstate Consort Fleur?
Yes.
But Meizhuang, I was without a choice.
Who wants to aid the enemy that has killed one's child?
Think about it from my perspective -
if it wasn't my only option,
why would I resort to this?
Meizhuang, I know you can't bear it,
but I have endured no less suffering than you.
Do you think I bear this easily?
Then tell me your reasons.
Think about it this way -
in order to appease Nian Gengyao,
His Majesty will reinstate Nian Shilan sooner or later,
at least her honorary name,
if not promoting her to Noble Consort, depending on the situation in court.
Even if the Empress Dowager favors you,
you can't hold your ground against Consort Nian.
Instead of watching that situation unfold,
I chose to be the person who suggested it
because His Majesty knows he has no choice, and
now will also feel guilty when he reinstates her.
As such feelings grow,
my position will be more stable.
You've explained it very clearly
but why am I still so confused?
With her title of Consort restored, won't it be even
easier for her to become a Noble Consort?
You may have calculated your moves,
but she won't necessarily act as you expect.
You're right.
I don't know when it was
that I became this calculating and selfish.
I know
I’m no longer the kind and innocent person I was.
But I did so
for reasons that are not easy to explain right now.
All right, all right.
You can have your reasons and I have my confusion.
"Half a sentence is too much conversation if poorly timed."
Is it because you want to use Consort Fleur to curry favor with Nian Genyao
because you've seen Nian Gengyao’s power grow?
Meizhuang,
am I so despicable in your eyes?
I have never forgotten
how I lost my child that day.
Huan’er,
we grew up together.
I've always known that my looks and wits
fade in comparison to you.
So I decided to cultivate my virtue and modesty.
You were good at dancing, so I focused on the zither.
My skills were never inferior to yours.
Then, we were selected to enter the palace together.
We always supported each other.
Even though His Majesty no longer favors me,
I never resented you in the least.
But I don’t know why,
looking at you now,
I feel that I’m so far behind.
You have Dr. Wen’s admiration
and His Majesty’s favor.
Your father has received honors from His Majesty.
Everything is going well for you.
But I ...
I have nothing.
I remember when we were little,
we set off paper boats into the river together.
The nursemaid said
the further the boats traveled,
the further from home we would marry.
But you said
both our boats had to travel the same distance
So we would marry in the same place -
ideally to two brothers.
Then we could stay together for the rest of our lives.
We are in the same place now.
But I never imagined our hearts could drift so far.
Meizhuang,
do you really intend to drift apart?
"Even the best banquet must come to an end."
It isn't a matter of drifting or not.
You can leave now,
and you need not visit if not necessary.
You will understand me one day.
Perhaps.
Meizhuang,
since you don’t wish to be disturbed,
I won't return until my goal is achieved.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty
- Peace to Your Highnesses.
- Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
It's nice that Lady Vertu is here as well.
I have not seen you together for a while.
I've been serving the Empress Dowager,
so I rarely venture to other palaces.
It's about time for Her Majesty to take her medicine.
Please allow me to take my leave.
All right.
I'm glad Her Majesty likes you.
You should visit her as much as possible.
Concubine Sourire, why don't you take a seat?
Lady Vertu has been behaving like that
to everyone recently.
Don't let it worry you.
Perhaps it is because of the weather
that Meizhuang has not been in good health?
The weather would not cause anything serious.
But women are fragile
and need to be taken better care of.
Don't be like Consort Honnête -
she began to have great trouble with her health.
Yes.
His Majesty told me that
you haven't seen your family since you entered the palace.
I've arranged for your mother to visit you today.
You can wait in the Palace of Pearl Jade.
I thank Your Majesty.
Go get ready for her visit.
Your mother and sister will arrive in the afternoon.
Yes.
Well then, you're all dismissed.
Lady An, please stay behind.
Yes.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Your Majesty.
You saw what happened just now, right?
Lady Vertu and Concubine Sourire
behave like strangers in the street.
Lady Vertu has a decent family background.
And Concubine Sourire's father has been
promoted several times.
If they were united,
I'm afraid it would only cause more trouble in the palace.
I agree with Your Majesty.
It would not be desirable if both Lady Vertu and Concubine
Sourire gained as much power as Consort Fleur.
I'm of the same mind.
His Majesty can favor anyone he likes,
but we can't allow a second Consort Fleur.
Mother, why are we still not at Huan's palace?
Don't complain.
We're in the Forbidden City.
There's nowhere under heaven bigger than this.
That's why it's a long trip.
Don't say anything foolish when you see your sister.
Do you understand?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Her Ladyship and your sister
are here to see Your Highness.
- Show them in instantly.
- Yes.
Mother.
Sister.
Allow me and my daughter Yurao to
kneel in respect before Your Highness.
May peace and grace be with Your Highness.
Please rise, please rise.
I thank Your Highness.
You must have had a very tiring trip, mother. Please sit.
Bring the tea, Jade.
Your Highness has become more distinguished in status
and Jade has grown more beautiful.
I thank Your Ladyship.
Mother, are you not going to compliment me?
Of course Your Highness has grown even more beautiful.
Sister, your shoes are so pretty.
Everything in this chamber is so gorgeous.
Yurao!
These shoes are just My Lady's everyday shoes.
She has a pair of jade shoes gifted by His Majesty.
They are made of Shu Brocade and studded with jewels.
These shoes don't even compare!
His Majesty treats Your Highness very well.
I heard that on my way here.
Please have some tea, Your Ladyship.
This is this year's "snowdrop jade",
a recent tribute to the palace.
It's too precious. I don't deserve to drink it.
Mother,
it's just a cup of tea.
I know you love tea,
please try some.
I'm grateful for Your Highness's concern.
This is Your Ladyship's favorite dessert.
My Lady prepared it early this morning.
My Lady was so happy to hear that
Your Ladyship would be visiting.
My Lady, Lady An sent Daisy here
to present some gifts to Her Ladyship.
I've set them aside.
You may go now.
I'd like to talk with my mother and sister.
Yes.
Let me look at you, Yurao.
My Lady.
Did you send the gifts over?
Yes, My Lady.
Good.
The Dong'e ejiao was specially offered by
the Governor of Shandong as a tribute.
I dare say it will be up to Her Ladyship's standards.
Well, you can go now.
Yes.
No matter who she is,
it's an honor to receive a gift from the palace.
I remember when I stayed at their estate,
everything there looked so exquisite to me.
Like nothing I'd ever seen.
Now
I can finally grant them something nice.
My Lady, you're so kind and
generous in expressing your gratitude.
More than expressing my gratitude,
it‘s that
I finally hold a superior status.
I'm not the one receiving gifts and graces anymore.
Congratulations, My Lady.
I wonder
when my parents will be able to visit me in the palace.
Don't worry, My Lady. That day will come.
Maybe ...
Her Ladyship will be able to come
when you are pregnant, My Lady,
But Her Majesty is not allowing me
to conceive an imperial heir.
Her Majesty will, eventually.
Rather than waiting for a child,
I'd prefer to wait until my favor
is equal to Concubine Sourire's.
Then my mother could visit the palace with tremendous pride.
Sister, are you happy living in the palace?
How does my brother-in-law treat you?
Brother-in-law?
His Majesty treats me exceptionally well.
But sometimes
I need to be very careful
of what I say,
and how I say it to please him.
It's quite tiring.
So that's why you look thinner.
Yes, I'm thinner.
You must have eaten so much over the New Year.
You look taller and chubbier than before.
Your Highness has lost some weight.
Has Your Highness recovered from your miscarriage?
Dr. Wen has been attending to my health.
It has improved a lot.
That's a relief.
After all, Your Highness is so young.
Your Highness will certainly have another child
when you've fully recovered.
Besides, Your Highness is in high favor with His Majesty.
To an outsider, it looks like I enjoy unending grandeur.
But in fact,
I find that "true affection is even
harder to come by than gold and treasures.”
Your Highness,
your heart may overflow with palace woes but withhold your words in front of the parrot.
Mother, you are very cautious.
Even for ordinary couples, you can never be too
careful in protecting your love and favor.
Let alone the imperial family.
His Majesty is also the monarch to Your Highness.
I'll remember your advice, mother.
Not only with His Majesty,
you need to be cautious in everything.
Consort Fleur has already exhausted you emotionally,
but there are still many others in the palace.
There's nothing wrong with
Your Highness being partial to Jade.
But if your maids dress so extravagantly,
it may furrow some eyebrows.
Jade and Vermilion grew up with me.
They are like sisters to me.
They are like your sisters.
But after all, they're not your sisters.
This is your sister.
Once you enter the palace, its vastness swallows you.
There's no point worrying about me.
We need to find a good family for Yurao.
So she can live an ordinary peaceful life.
Her personality is a lot like Your Highness's.
I'm afraid that might be difficult.
That's why I have to bring honor to my family.
For you, for father, and also for Yurao.
We know how you feel.
Your father is so worried day and night.
He regrets that wasn't able to do more for you in court
so that your life could be peaceful in the harem.
Your Highness,
it's time for Her Ladyship and your sister to return.
Your Highness, we should be leaving.
You just got here, now you're leaving?
Can't you stay for longer?
It's not appropriate to stay in the palace for too long
lest anyone say you have grown conceited over your favor.
Actually, your father did not want me to visit.
Others will see it as a privilege granted to your family.
After I leave,
I don't know when I will be able to see Your Highness again.
Your Highness
will have only yourself to count on.
Mother, don't worry.
Let's go.
Sourire's family came to visit.
They only stayed briefly.
That must be hard on her.
It's not easy for her to see her family.
My family used to visit frequently.
Now Concubine Sourire has finally managed to earn this honor.
His Majesty promoted her father.
But it is only a matter of expediency.
He's still a civil official after all.
He has no prospects.
His Majesty the Emperor.
What's so funny?
Peace to Your Majesty.
Rise.
I was just joking with Song Zhi,
saying how the weather is getting hotter and hotter,
and how I would love to
go to the Summer Palace with Your Majesty.
If we stay here, we will become roasted yams.
When have I ever been to the Summer Palace without you?
- Your Majesty, let's eat after you've washed your hands
- Certainly.
I had my kitchen prepare many of
Your Majesty's favorite dishes.
Great!
What did you add to the herbal powder?
It's different than before.
It used to be made with spikenard, angelica,
cassia twig and bamboo leaves
soaked with pork spleen.
This was then sun-dried and crushed into the washing powder.
Her Highness dislikes the smell of cassia twig,
so I used magnolia bark instead,
and added sandalwood.
It's more moisturizing and fragrant.
I didn't know you were so well-versed in such things.
Her Highness is careful about everything she uses.
So I always select them attentively and try them out first.
It's fortunate that you know all this
and your hands are also quite fair.
That's why Consort Fleur would trust
what you've tried for her.
Your name is... Song Zhi?
Your Majesty, my family name is Qiao.
The name Song Zhi was granted to me by Her Highness.
Zhi as in angelica, a fragrant herb and a sweet name.
Let's eat.
Yes.
Just have the servants do it.
You don't need to serve me yourself.
Song Zhi,
come here and serve me.
His Majesty asked you to serve him, do it carefully.
Yes.
Your kitchen makes excellent food.
It's only good if Your Majesty likes it.
Otherwise, it's not good at all, regardless of the taste.
What profound words!
I am the worst with words.
But your servants are very articulate.
You've had a good influence on them.
Your Majesty is right.
Vertu, I haven't seen you spending time with Sourire recently.
What happened?
His Majesty visits her frequently,
so it's not convenient for me to see her.
And I've been busy serving the Empress Dowager,
so I haven't had a chance to run into her.
That's a relief.
I was overthinking.
I thought the three of us were drifting apart
as we haven't seen each other much recently.
What makes you think that?
As sisters, we are always honest with each other.
Why would we ever drift?
I should not have asked such a question,
I thought over it too much.
I apologize.
I know you often overthink things.
Otherwise, you wouldn't have kindly made the trip
to let me know about Concubine Sourire's
role in reinstating Consort Fleur.
I told you because I was worried.
I care about you and Sourire.
Do you?
If you really cared,
you wouldn't have had Coua telling me that on your behalf.
What Concubine Sourire did was not right.
But did you really tell me out of
the goodness of your heart?
You have misunderstood me, Vertu.
I resent Consort Fleur in the same way you do.
So I was worried that Sourire was doing something foolish.
If you were worried about her,
you could have told her directly.
Please don't be mad, Vertu.
I'm not good at communicating my heart
and ended up making you upset.
Forget it.
If you have time to explain yourself to me,
you might as well put some effort into
getting into His Majesty's good graces
and convincing him to punish Consort Fleur.
I do not have the ability to convince him.
Inability isn't an issue.
What is an issue, is having a corrupt heart and intentionally driving a wedge between people.
I appreciate your advice.
I had no intention to give any advice.
We've known each other for a while,
so we can speak to one another directly.
We don't have to speak to each other sideways.
That is just tiring.
If you have such concerns in the future,
you can tell her yourself.
I don't need to hear it.
Lady Vertu was very plain-spoken.
It seems her temperament became tougher
since she fell out of favor.
Her temperament has always been like this.
It never changed.
What are they carrying?
This road leads to the Palace of Pearl Jade.
It's probably some herbal tonics.
Is Concubine Sourire still taking tonics?
I heard that Her Highness's constitution
has been weak since her miscarriage
so His Majesty specially ordered some herbs for her.
As expected,
of the three of us,
Concubine Sourire gained the highest favor in the end.
Her Majesty is right.
While Concubine Sourire is in favor,
being close with her
is also being close to favor.
But after Concubine Sourire's recovery,
she stopped seeing you so frequently, My Lady.
If she doesn't visit me, I'll just go visit her.
Ask for a good formula from the Imperial Infirmary
and collect the herbs accordingly.
Yes.
You were impressively verbose at dinner.
Why have you gone so quiet now?
I beg Your Highness's forgiveness.
What did you do wrong
that I need to forgive?
Weren't you pleased with yourself
waving your paws about before His Majesty!
- I ...
- Your Highness.
Your Highness.
If Your Highness dislikes this comb,
you can give it to me as a reward.
It would be a pity to throw it away.
Song Zhi,
Her Highness's prenatal tonics are brewing outside.
Why don't you go watch over the stove?
Your Highness need not be angry.
It was just a mindless compliment from His Majesty.
It doesn't mean anything.
His Majesty will not be pleased if he knows
Your Highness got angry about it.
Now even my own palace has a sly minx!
Quick-witted and honey-mouthed
and waving her paws about over nothing!
Your Highness, all the women in the palace
are here to serve His Majesty.
I understand that Your Highness cares for His Majesty.
But since Your Highness has just regained favor,
even if His Majesty is fond of Song Zhi,
Your Highness has to act generously.
So that His Majesty does not feel that
Your Highness is jealous or intolerant.
Your Highness, what matters most
is His Majesty's favor.
I will banish her from the palace tomorrow.
She can't see His Majesty again.
Your Highness should not reveal any anger on your face.
Rather, when Your Highness is with His Majesty,
you must be particularly nice to Song Zhi.
This way, His Majesty will perceive your generosity
and it will stop the gossip in the palace.
I have nothing to be ashamed of!
Your Highness, rumors can be truly frightful.
You think I'm afraid of rumors?
I only fear that His Majesty might believe them.
I know Your Highness cares about His Majesty the most.
Reward this to Song Zhi.
Your Highness is enlightened.
I will go give it to her now.
Coua, bring over the medicine.
Is it ready?
Yes, as you bade me, My Lady.
Did you use herbs of the finest quality?
Only the best.
Good.
Sourire is frail.
She needs the nourishment.
What are you doing, My Lady?
Even the best ingredients call for a catalyst.
Human blood is the best catalyst.
My Lady, your noble body cannot be damaged.
Please take my blood instead.
No, I can do it.
My Lady, please don't.
Stop!
Jade, what time is it?
Sourire, you woke up.
Why are you here?
I brewed this tonic in my palace
It's been kept warm on the stove.
It was prepared according to Dr. Wen's formula
with a few additional nourishing herbs.
You will have a speedy recovery if you take this.
But Dr. Wen has not
prescribed new herbs for me recently.
You should have some while it's warm.
What's in the tonic? It has a strong smell.
Here.
Don't worry.
I've had some of it. It's safe.
Do you not trust me, Sourire?
What happened to your wrist?
Oh ...
Nothing, it was an accident.
What happened?
My goodness, what happened?
Even though you have now recovered from your miscarriage,
you have still been feeling weak.
I consulted some ancient formulae
and they say that human blood can bring out
the nourishing elements of herbs.
So I tried using my blood
I hope that it can help improve your health
and prepare you for another pregnancy.
Were you out of your mind?
You can't trust ancient formulae!
I'm not even ill.
My health will recover with nourishing herbs.
I don't care.
All I want is for you to be in good health
and to be able to have another child.
After you regained favor from His Majesty,
I have been feeling distant from you, Sourire.
I don't know if that's because of His Majesty's favor for me
or my inability to prevent Consort Fleur
punishing you in her courtyard.
I could only watch as you lost your child.
Lingrong, don't dwell on it.
I have no one else to rely on in this palace
other than you and His Majesty.
If you distanced yourself from me
because of His Majesty's favor to me,
I would rather have you than His Majesty.
Lingrong, that's not what I meant.
- It's just ...
- Sourire.
Meizhuang has already drifted apart from us.
Will you also turn me away?
The three of us entered the palace together.
Although I didn't grow up with you as she did,
there's not a day I'm not grateful
for the time your family took care of me.
Yes,
but even if you wanted to help me,
why did you have to harm yourself?
Because you are the only one who will help me!
If you do not trust me,
who else can I trust
in the harem?
You're right.
“Beauty withers in the snap of a finger.
But favor fades even before age.”
Only you and Meizhuang
will "sit with me by the incense burner until dawn"
[from a poem about a concubine who lost favor]
No, Sourire,
you will never be out of favor.
I will always be by your side
to keep you company.
It's all right.
Don't be sad.
If you have the heart to,
you can copy some sutras for my child.
I hope he will reach the Pure Land.
You didn't need to ask. I have already copied some.
I appreciate it.
I've been feeling fatigued recently.
May I trouble you to bring my copies to the Baohua Hall
so they can send it to my child?
It's all I can do for him, as his mother.
If you give your copies to me,
I will go right away.
Jade, bring the sutras
and go with Lady An.
Yes.
I will let you rest, Sourire.
I will take my leave now.
My Lady, are you going to drink it?
I don't take any medicine that is not prescribed by Dr. Wen.
Discard it.
Lady An cares for you from her heart, My Lady.
Care does not reside in an object.
Whether she cut herself or not,
I hope her heart harbors some sincerity.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
https://magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.